drsuemorter.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy – Dr. Sue Morter

Welcome to DrSueMorter.com

This full Statement of Privacy applies to Morter Institute and the Dr. Sue Morter LLC website (drsuemorter.com) and governs data collection and usage. When you access and use drsuemorter.com, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of Personal Information**

Visitors to drsuemorter.com may be asked to share personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, first and last name. If you purchase our products or register for one of our courses or programs you can be asked your home address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, and billing information (such as a credit card number). When you sign up for one of our free meditations or our email newsletter, or purchase one of our products or services, you’ll receive information about that product and occasional information about other related products, programs and events we feel you would find relevant.

**How to “Unsubscribe”**

If you wish to stop receiving emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time using the link provided at the bottom of all our emails. If you continue to receive emails from us after unsubscribing, it usually means you have registered with us using an additional email address. If you have any trouble unsubscribing, please call us at 855-872-8700 or email info@drsuemorter.com.

**Will My Information Ever Be Shared?**

We do not rent, share or sell your information.

**Computer Hardware and Software Information**

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by the systems used by Morter Institute. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Morter Institute to ensure that the information we provide is working properly across all platforms, as well for the general operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of drsuemorter.com to improve our services to you.

**Sharing on Public Blog Comments**

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or by commenting through any of Dr. Sue Morter blogs or groups, this information may be collected and used by others. We suggest that you do not share your email address or any other private information when commenting publicly.

**Affiliated Websites**

Morter Institute may share resources such as books, articles or other free or paid information from other websites. If you choose to visit any of these websites, we encourage you to review the privacy statements of those websites so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information.

Morter Institute is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of drsuemorter.com.

**Trusted Partners**

In order to deliver our emails, ship any products you order, provide customer and technical support and generally provide services to you, Morter Institute may share data with trusted partners. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Morter Institute and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Morter Institute does not collect, use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Morter Institute keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within drsuemorter.com. We do this in order to determine what content, coursework, tours and services are the most popular. This data may be used to deliver customized content within drsuemorter.com to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

**Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to Comply with Law**

Morter Institute and the Dr. Sue Morter website will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Morter Institute or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Morter Institute; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Morter Institute, or the public.

**Use of Cookies**

The Dr. Sue Morter website uses a very common practice of using “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience (Many websites use cookies and you can easily identify them in any browser). A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Morter Institute pages, or register with Morter Institute site or services, a cookie helps Morter Institute to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of websites you visit.

**Security of Personal Information**

Morter Institute secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Morter Institute secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

**Correcting Inaccuracies in Personal Information**

You may contact us at 855-872-8700 to update your Personal Information or correct inaccuracies.

**Updates to Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy was last updated and posted on May 24, 2018.

Morter Institute will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect privacy requirement updates, company policy and customer feedback.

**Contact Information**

Morter Institute  
10439 Commerce Drive, Suite 140  
Carmel, IN 46032  
855-872-8700
